

Yesun-Erdene Jargalsaikhan

O Home: Door 21, Apt. 2, 4 khoroo, Bayangol district, 16052, Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

Email: yesuuygls@gmail.com Phone: (+976) 99401008

₩ebsite: https://yesunerdene.github.io/yesunerdene/ ▶ Viber: +97699401008

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yesunerdene-jargalsaikhan-b46398162/

Gender: Female **Date of birth:** 09/09/1999 **Nationality:** Mongolian

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with a solid aspiration to expand my professional capacity into data science; I am particularly ambitious to develop an eye-tracking technology dedicated to people with movement disabilities using machine learning. I have experience in software development, especially mobile application development of 3.5 years and other software development in the IT industry in Mongolia; also professional in the whole mobile application project development process.

EDUCATION

[01/09/2016 - 12/06/2020] **Bachelor in Software Engineering**

National University of Mongolia, School of Engineering and Applied Science www.num.edu.mn

Final grade: GPA 3.5 / 4.0 (Top 10 out of 200 graduates)

Thesis: The real estate advertisement for renting or selling platform based on a map. Based on the thesis, I developed a mobile application and a website for a real estate platform, which includes marketing, purchasing and auctioning features. (Thesis final mark: 96A).

SKILLS

Software engineering

- The whole process of mobile application development from the blank project to release and launch to public application stores
- · Project planning, designing, developing, delivering, testing and maintaining.

Framework & Technologies

• React Native |S | React |S | Symfony (PHP) | Laravel (PHP)

Programming and scripting languages

• C | C++ | Java | Python | Javascript | PHP | HTML, modest experience in R **DBMS Query languages**

· MySQL, MSSQL, SQL, Graphql

Version control systems

Git

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Mongolian

Other language(s):

English (IELTS 6.5)

LISTENING C1 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Russian

LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

WORK EXPERIENCE

[10/01/2022 – Current] Software engineer (full-time)

Octagon LLC

Tasks: Taking responsibility for the whole mobile application project developement of Octagon ecosystem and a governmental pedometer project named AND: Walk & Earn.

Projects: Octagon - mobile application for digital wallet and NFT & Crypto marketplace, AND: Walk & Earn - pedometer app.

[16/09/2019 – 10/01/2022] **Software engineer**

Digital Mall LLC

At the beginning of my 4th year of study in software engineering, my former internship employer company offered me to work as a software developer in their e-commerce system. I worked as a part-time software developer until I obtained my undergraduate degree, and afterwards, I worked as a full-time software engineer at the company.

Tasks: Took responsibility for the whole mobile application project development of the mobile application, core backend development, the admin panel of the e-commerce platform and for database support engineering.

Projects: Banana Mall (e-commerce mobile application and a website.)

[01/02/2021 - 10/01/2022] **Software engineer (remote)**

Powered LLC https://powered.mn/

Tasks: Took responsibility for the whole mobile application project developement of YESH.MN **Projects:** YESH.MN - test-based learning mobile application for high school students.

[01/07/2020 - 01/01/2023]

Software developer (remote)

Alpha Labs LLC

Tasks: Took responsibility for the whole mobile application project developement of following mobile applications:

Projects: BSB.mn, G-Power monitoring, ISU Mongolia and 100ail market.

PROJECTS

[01/01/2022 - Current] **Octagon Wallet**

Mobile application of Octagon Ecosystem - crypto exchange & NFT marketplace, and a digital wallet. (React Native Js). Released in 03/2022. (Apple app store and Google play store), Introduction

[10/02/2021 - 01/01/2023] YESH.MN

Mobile application of YESH.MN - test-based learning mobile application for high school students preparing for the university general entrance examination (React Native JS). Released 05/2021 (Ap ple app store and Google play store) Introduction

[16/09/2019 - 01/01/2022] **Banana Mall**

- · Mobile application of BananaMall for e-commerce of online shopping and delivery service. (Re act Native JS)
- Core system for the corresponding platform (Symfony PHP, MySQL)
- Admin panel of the e-commerce (React JS)

[11/2019] Released the ecommerce website, https://bananamall.mn

[11/2021] Released the mobile application, Apple store and Google Play store

[01/07/2020 - 01/01/2022] **BSB.mn**

Mobile application of BSB.MN for e-commerce of online shopping and delivery service (React Native JS). Released 11/2021 (Apple app store and Google play store)

[01/10/2022 - 01/12/2022] **ISU Mongolia**

Mobile application of mobile portal application for parents of students and employees of "International School of Ulaanbaatar", for managing various kinds of activity in the school (React Native IS).

[01/06/2022 - 01/09/2022] **G-Solar**

Mobile application for the consumers of power supply company, named "G-power", for monitoring and surveillance of power consumption of their activity (React Native JS). Released in 12/2022 (Go ogle play store)

[01/11/2022 - 31/12/2022] AND: Walk & Earn

Mobile application for the statistics on walking of the whole national citizens. Works like a pedometer and rewards the person who reached the targeted number of steps (React Native JS). [18/05/2019 - 31/12/2019] **Togloom Trade**

E-sport game virtual item selling website (Laravel PHP). https://togloom.trade/

[23/07/2019 - 24/08/2019] **Dynamic Survey platform**

Developed a dynamic survey form platform during my internship at And Systems LLC (Slim PHP).

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

[23/07/2019 - 23/08/2019] Internship at And Systems LLC

During the software developer internship, I developed:

- cation sérvice using Python
- Dynamic create-able survey form platform using Symfony(PHP)

Certified Information Technology Professionals (IP, FE)

ITPEC /Information Technology Professionals Examination Council/, successfully passed:

[11/12/2018] Information Technology Passport Examination - /MNIP18A0009/

[28/10/2019] Fundamental Information Technology Engineer Examination - /MNFE19A0008/

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

[27/05/2019 - 29/05/2019] Open Data Hackathon - 2019 - National University of Mongolia

Participated as a team in the students' competition to build a new platform using open data from the National University of Mongolia within two days. Our team innovated a platform which generates various kinds of data visualization with open data using *R language*.

[17/05/2019 - 19/05/2019] Open Platform Hackathon - LendMN - 2019 (awarded 2nd place)

Participated as a team and won 2nd place in building a new platform competition within two days. Our team innovated and developed a new idea for an e-sport game item-selling platform. I contributed my ideas and worked on the web development of the platform using Laravel (PHP). http s://ikon.mn/n/1kvt

[16/10/2020 - 18/10/2020] Hackathon - AND Systems - 2020 (awarded 1st place)

Participated as a team and won 1st place in building a new platform competition within two days. Our team innovated and developed a new idea of a task management extension for "Visual studio" code editor", which allows managing all job tasks for developers in their code editor. I contributed my ideas and worked on developing the extension using *Typescript* programming language.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Employee of the year 2022 - Octagon LLC

[12/2022] Encouragement: For being exceptional and driven towards the company value.

Olympiads and competitions

- [03/2014] Kangaroo-2014 International Mathematical Competition Honorable certification
- [05/2013] 7th Mathematics Olympiad 3rd place Administration of Orkhon province
- [05/2013] 7th Mathematics Olympiad 2nd place (team)- Administration of Orkhon province
- [05/2013] Linguistics Olympiad 3rd place *Administration of Orkhon province* [01/2011] Mathematics Olympiad 3rd place *Administration of "Erdenet" high school*

HOBBIES

Sports and interests

- Archer target archery compound style
- Figure skating self educating
- · Volleyball former libero in a local team
- · Making handcraft furniture
- Knitting & crocheting
- Acrylic painting

DRIVING LICENCE

Cars: B